<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="//tratamentes.pt/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright>© Tratamentes</copyright><description>Tratamentes</description><language>pt-pt</language><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/</link><title>Tratamentes</title><item><description><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/massagem-desportiva.webp" alt="Technician helps the client relax his back muscles, while applying one of the Swedish massage techniques" title="Técnico auxilia cliente a relaxar a musculatura dorsal, ao aplicar uma das técnica da massagem sueca"></p>
<p>A full body massage that uses smooth, fluid movements that help improve circulation and provide well-being.</p>
<p>The rush of everyday life generates several moments of stress and tension that accumulate and can negatively affect health and well-being. Relaxation massage is an excellent way to relieve and reduce these effects, through smooth and fluid movements that improve circulation, reduce tension, and promote a state of peace and tranquility.</p>
<p>Allow yourself to enjoy 60 minutes of tranquility, while recovering your energy and inner strength. Feel your body renewed and ready to face the day-to-day demands. Schedule your relaxation massage session now.</p>
<ul>
<li>Duration: 60 min.</li>
<li>Price: 60 euros</li>
</ul>
<p>For <strong><a href="https://buk.pt/tratamentes">appointments</a></strong> and more information <strong><a href="/contact">contact me</a></strong></p>
<p><em><strong>Notes</strong></em>:</p>
<ul>
<li>You should indicate only one type of massage per session.</li>
<li>The transportation up to 5km from the center of Parede, Cascais county, is included in the price. For distances over 5km, an additional fee of 1.20 euros per kilometer.</li>
<li>Payments by MBWay, cash or immediate bank transfer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/massagem-sueca/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/massagem-sueca/</link><title>Swedish or Relaxation Massage</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<p>The Californian Massage is a journey of well-being for your body, mind and soul. For 90 minutes, you will be enveloped by gentle movements that gradually become deep and extensive, helping you to release accumulated stress and anxiety, providing a sense of serenity and balance. Its unique combination of massage techniques and essential oils allows you to immerse yourself in a world of comfort and rejuvenation, feeling more confident and prepared to face day-to-day problems.</p>
<p>Book now and enjoy the unique experience that is Californian Massage.</p>
<ul>
<li>Duration: 90 min.</li>
<li>Price: 90 euros</li>
</ul>
<p>For <strong><a href="https://buk.pt/tratamentes">appointments</a></strong> and more information <strong><a href="/contact">contact me</a></strong></p>
<p><em><strong>Notes</strong></em>:</p>
<ul>
<li>You should indicate only one type of massage per session.</li>
<li>The transportation up to 5km from the center of Parede, Cascais county, is included in the price. For distances over 5km, an additional fee of 1.20 euros per kilometer.</li>
<li>Payments by MBWay, cash or immediate bank transfer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/tobeimplemented/massagem-californiana/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/tobeimplemented/massagem-californiana/</link><title>Californian Massage</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/massagem-desportiva.webp" alt="Técnico auxilia atleta a recuperar" title="Técnico auxilia atleta a recuperar"></p>
<p>If you are an athlete or simply an amateur sportsman looking to improve your performance and prevent injuries, sports massage is a fundamental technique to achieve your goals.</p>
<p>With my experience and knowledge, I can offer a personalised massage that meets your specific needs.</p>
<p>From the application of appropriate techniques, such as manipulations and stretching, to the use of more up-to-date recovery protocols such as &ldquo;PEACE &amp; LOVE&rdquo;, I will be by your side at every stage, ensuring you have the best possible support.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t wait any longer to take care of your body in an efficient and professional way, schedule your sports massage session with me right now.</p>
<ul>
<li>Duration: 30 min.</li>
<li>Price: 30 euros</li>
</ul>
<p>For <strong><a href="https://buk.pt/tratamentes">appointments</a></strong> and more information <strong><a href="/contact">contact me</a></strong></p>
<p><em><strong>Notes</strong></em>:</p>
<ul>
<li>You should indicate only one type of massage per session.</li>
<li>The transportation up to 5km from the center of Parede, Cascais county, is included in the price. For distances over 5km, an additional fee of 1.20 euros per kilometer.</li>
<li>Payments by MBWay, cash or immediate bank transfer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/massagem-desportiva/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/massagem-desportiva/</link><title>Massagem Desportiva (pré e pós treino)</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[




































































    









    





    
        
    



    


<figure class=" d-flex   float-end   justify-content-center    ms-4  paige-figure "  style="width: 50%" >
    
        <div  class=" overflow-auto"  >
    

    
        <div class="d-table">
    

    <div class="text-center"><img   class="img-fluid rounded"  crossorigin="anonymous"   height="724"  loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" src="/img/DLM_1280x724.df1ab0720b5655f23630aa429feba9c64482094ba113ac1f9cdb4229f437b5fc.webp"    width="1280" ></div>

    
        <figcaption class="figure-caption  text-center"  style="caption-side: bottom; display: table-caption" >Application of DLM - Manual Lymphatic Drainage</figcaption>
    

    
        </div>
    

    
        </div>
    
</figure>



<p>If you have ever experienced swollen limbs or discomfort due to lymphedema, lymphatic drainage massage may help you.</p>
<p>This gentle massage technique is designed to stimulate the lymphatic system, which can help relieve the painful swelling caused by lymphedema.</p>
<p>In this blog article on &ldquo;<a href="/en/blog/drenagem-linfatica-manual/">Lymphatic drainage massage: What you need to know</a>&rdquo; is what you need to know about lymphatic drainage massage and how it can benefit your health.</p>
<p>Lymphatic drainage massage, also known as manual lymphatic drainage is a specialised massage technique that targets the lymphatic system.</p>
<p>The aim of lymph drainage massage is to improve the flow of lymph, which can become blocked due to surgery, injury or illness.</p>
<p>Lymphatic drainage massage is commonly used to relieve swelling and discomfort caused by lymphedema, one of the conditions that can occur, such as after breast cancer surgery.</p>
<ul>
<li>Price: 60 €</li>
<li>Duration: 60 min.</li>
</ul>
<p>You can <strong><a href="https://buk.pt/tratamentes">book a session here </a></strong> and for more information <strong><a href="/contact">contact me</a></strong></p>
<p>_ <strong>Notes</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>You must indicate only one type of massage per session.</li>
<li>The transportation until 5km from the centre of Parede, Cascais county, is included in the price. For distances greater than 5km, there is an additional charge of 1.20 euros per kilometer.</li>
<li>Payments by MBWay, cash or immediate bank transfer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/drenagem-linfatica-manual/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/drenagem-linfatica-manual/</link><title>Lymphatic Drainage Massage (LDM)</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<p>As a technician specialized in massage therapy I would like to suggest a natural and effective solution to treat a variety of physical and emotional problems.</p>
<p>Using proven techniques such as Muscle Energetic Technique, Muscle Inhibition Technique or Jones technique, Joint Mobilization, Neuromuscular Techniques and Harmonic Techniques, I can help treat chronic pain, muscle injuries, postural problems, anxiety, depression or insomnia.</p>
<p>I believe that massage therapy is much more than just a massage, and I am committed to providing the best possible treatment to help my clients achieve their health and wellness goals.</p>
<p>So if you are looking for a natural and effective way to treat your physical or emotional problems, I am here to help.</p>
<p>Duration: 60 min.
Price: 60 euros</p>
<p>For <strong><a href="https://buk.pt/tratamentes">appointments</a></strong> and more information <strong><a href="/contact">contact me</a></strong></p>
<p><em><strong>Notes</strong></em>:</p>
<ul>
<li>You should indicate only one type of massage per session.</li>
<li>The transportation up to 5km from the center of Parede, Cascais county, is included in the price. For distances over 5km, an additional fee of 1.20 euros per kilometer.</li>
<li>Payments by MBWay, cash or immediate bank transfer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/massagem-terapeutica/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/massagem-terapeutica/</link><title>Therapeutic Massage</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[












































































    







    


<figure class=" d-flex    justify-content-center    paige-figure " >
    
        <div  class=" overflow-auto"   style="width: 50%" >
    

    

    <div class="text-center"><img   class="img-fluid rounded"  crossorigin="anonymous"   height="724"  loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" src="/img/DLM_1280x724.df1ab0720b5655f23630aa429feba9c64482094ba113ac1f9cdb4229f437b5fc.webp"    width="1280" ></div>

    
        <figcaption class="figure-caption  text-center" >Application of DLM - Manual Lymphatic Drainage</figcaption>
    

    

    
        </div>
    
</figure>



<p>If you have ever experienced swollen limbs or discomfort due to lymphedema, lymphatic drainage massage may help you. This gentle massage technique is designed to stimulate the lymphatic system, which can help relieve painful swelling caused by lymphedema. Below is what you need to know about lymphatic drainage massage and how it can benefit your health.</p>
<h2 id="i-overview">I. Overview</h2>
<p>Lymphatic drainage massage, also known as manual lymphatic drainage, is a specialized massage technique that targets the lymphatic system. The goal of lymph drainage massage is to improve the flow of lymph, which may become obstructed due to surgery, injury, or illness. In particular, lymphatic drainage massage is commonly used to relieve swelling and discomfort caused by lymphedema, one of the conditions that can occur, such as after breast cancer surgery.</p>
<h2 id="ii-details-of-the-procedure">II. Details of the procedure</h2>
<p>The lymphatic drainage massage technique involves a two-step process which are as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>cleansing</li>
<li>reabsorption.</li>
</ul>
<p>During the cleansing phase, the therapist gently massages the lymph nodes to encourage the lymph fluid to move towards the affected area. In the reabsorption phase, the therapist uses light pressure to help the lymphatic system reabsorb the fluid.</p>
<p>Mechanical lymphatic drainage massage devices such as compression pumps can also be used as an alternative to traditional massage techniques, however, systolic and diastolic blood pressure values should be noted as well as heart and respiratory rate, a cardiovascular risk assessment should also be done before using the mechanical pumping system.</p>
<h2 id="iii-risksbenefits">III. Risks/Benefits</h2>
<p>Lymphatic drainage massage is generally considered safe and can provide numerous benefits for those suffering from lymphedema.</p>
<p>With the application of lymphatic drainage massage, there are benefits in the following pathologies:</p>
<ul>
<li>Lymphedema</li>
<li>Fibromyalgia</li>
<li>Rheumatoid Arthritis</li>
<li>Chronic fatigue syndrome</li>
<li>Migraines</li>
</ul>
<p>It is important to make it clear that, despite being a gentle mobilisation technique, there are still some risks associated with lymphatic drainage massage. In some cases, massage can worsen the symptoms of lymphedema, so it may be recommended that you consult the professional who will be applying the manual lymphatic drainage massage before undergoing this treatment.</p>
<p>Lymphatic drainage massage should also be avoided if you have certain health conditions such as active infections, blood clots, heart condition or kidney failure.</p>
<h2 id="iv-recovery-and-outlook">IV. Recovery and Outlook</h2>
<p>After lymphatic drainage massage, you may experience immediate effects such as reduced swelling and pain. Long-term effects may include improved immune function and decreased risk of infection. Your massage therapist may also suggest lymphatic drainage massage techniques that you can apply to yourself in the comfort of your home.</p>
<p>Knowing that the human body functions as an organism with twelve interconnected systems, it is important to monitor your symptoms and inform your lymphatic drainage massage therapist, about its effectiveness in managing your health condition.</p>
<p>If you experience any side effects, such as fever or resurgence of edema with greater intensity it is important to seek medical attention.</p>
<h2 id="v-recent-literature-and-medical-advice">V. Recent literature and medical advice</h2>
<p>A quick PubMed search on lymphatic drainage massage methods (Vodder, LeDuc), reveals that this therapeutic approach is undoubtedly an excellent way for those suffering from disorders of the lymphatic and cardiovascular system, such as oedema and lymphedema.</p>
<p>According to the European Portal on Rare Diseases and Orphan Drugs (Orphanet), the prevalence of this disease is 1-5/10 000, making primary lymphoedema one of the rare diseases.</p>
<h2 id="vi-conclusion">VI. Conclusion</h2>
<p>A person can use lymphatic drainage massage techniques to help reduce swelling and improve circulation. An effectively functioning lymphatic system is essential for overall health.</p>
<p>It is important to know that with proper care and treatment, it is possible to manage symptoms and improve quality of life.</p>
<p>Learn more about how to book this <a href="/en/services/en/drenagem-linfatica-manual/">Lymphatic Manual Drainage</a> online</p>
]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/blog/drenagem-linfatica-manual/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/blog/drenagem-linfatica-manual/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><title>Lymphatic Drainage Massage: What You Need to Know</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<p>Paige provides a <code>paige/search</code> layout for site search.</p>
<p>Example <code>config.yaml</code>:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">outputs</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w">  </span><span class="nt">home</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s2">&#34;html&#34;</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">&#34;json&#34;</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">&#34;rss&#34;</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span></code></pre></div><p>Example <code>content/layouts/search.md</code>:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nn">---</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w"></span><span class="nt">layout</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="l">paige/search</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w"></span><span class="nt">title</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="l">Search Layout</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w"></span><span class="nn">---</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span></code></pre></div><p>Result:</p>]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/layouts/search/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/layouts/search/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><title>Search Layout</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="improving-your-health-and-quality-of-life-today">Improving your health and quality of life today</h2>
<p>Do you know that in Portugal at least 1 in 3 people (37%) live with chronic pain?</p>
<p>Chronic pain is a health problem, worldwide, that affects millions of people and can have a major impact on their quality of life.</p>
<p>Living with chronic pain can be challenging as it affects your daily life and social roles.</p>
<p>In the biopsychosocial view, pain management, addresses the psychological and social consequences that chronic pain can have, as well as the importance of considering biological, psychological and social factors in the assessment and treatment of chronic pain. It is well known that chronic pain can affect quality of life, relationships and the ability to perform daily activities.</p>
<p>To better understand the causes of pain it is important to understand the difference between primary and secondary chronic pain for better pain management.</p>
<p>Primary chronic pain is pain that is not caused by any other health condition, but is a condition in itself. For example, chronic headache is a primary pain.</p>
<p>Secondary chronic pain is that which is caused by an underlying health condition, such as arthritis or nerve damage.</p>



















































































    


<figure class="     paige-figure " >
    

    

    <div class="text-center"><img   class="img-fluid rounded"  crossorigin="anonymous"   height="827"  loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" src="/img/classificacao-da-dor-de-acordo-com-a-iasp-2021.341622c90f2bab450f500f2408a7bc50c030785057aa51a22705c59101207a2a.png"    width="1128" ></div>

    
        <figcaption class="figure-caption  text-center" >Pain Classification according to IASP 2021</figcaption>
    

    

    
</figure>



<p>It is important to note that some chronic pain can be a sign of a more serious health problem and therefore you should be alert to some of the symptoms such as fever, unexplained weight loss, muscle weakness, changes in sensitivity or progressive and persistent pain. If you experience any of these symptoms you should seek medical attention immediately.</p>
<p>Along with other professionals, such as musculoskeletal therapists (massage therapists, osteopaths, physiotherapists), doctors and pharmacists, psychology also has a role in the treatment of chronic pain, observing case by case and intervening to help the brain communicate in a healthier way with the body, thus reorganising the patient&rsquo;s brain function.</p>
<p>To improve their health, it is essential to change habits and patterns of behaviour.</p>
<p>The individual with chronic pain is an integral part of the process, so it is important that there is communication, with information and guidance, to help them understand the importance of their active participation in the treatment. Their collaboration is fundamental for the success of the treatment, since they are the ones who must perform the tasks and make the changes in their daily lives that contribute to improving their state of health.</p>
<p>Massage has been by choice, a treatment option for chronic pain, in particular for secondary chronic pain.</p>
<p>Based on scientific evidence, massage is indicated by medicine, as a way to relieve pain in most cases. For example, a 2011 study published in the journal Annals of Internal Medicine<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>, another study shows, that after applying massage there is a significant reduction of pain<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup>.</p>
<p>For those who suffer on a daily basis with chronic pain, the use of musculoskeletal manual therapy, by a qualified professional is a condition for the relief of pain, in order to restore the functionality of the affected limb or the body in general.</p>
<p>It is always important to mention, that depending on the pain mechanism, there may be a need for a more comprehensive approach, including other health care professionals, with the purpose of supporting chronic pain management.</p>
<p>Contact TrataMentœs today to schedule your first appointment and start experiencing the many benefits of regular massage.</p>
<hr>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Cherkin, D. C., Sherman, K. J., Kahn, J., Wellman, R., Cook, A. J., Johnson, E., Erro, J., Delaney, K., &amp; Deyo, R. A. (2011). A comparison of the effects of 2 types of massage and usual care on chronic low back pain. Annals of Internal Medicine, 155(1), 1. <a href="https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-155-1-201107050-00002">https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-155-1-201107050-00002</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Adams, R., White, B., &amp; Beckett, C. (2010). The effects of massage therapy on pain management in the acute care setting. International journal of therapeutic massage &amp; bodywork, 3(1), 4–11. <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3091428/pdf/ijtmb-3-1-4.pdf">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3091428/pdf/ijtmb-3-1-4.pdf</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/blog/viver-com-dor-cr%C3%B3nica-em-portugal-compreender-as-causas-e-procurar-tratamento-eficaz/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/blog/viver-com-dor-cr%C3%B3nica-em-portugal-compreender-as-causas-e-procurar-tratamento-eficaz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><title>Living with Chronic Pain in Portugal</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="improving-your-health-and-quality-of-life-today">Improving your health and quality of life today</h2>
<p>As we age, our bodies tend to slow down physiological processes, and with the challenges of modern life, the body accumulates more and more stress, in the majority of the population, leading to chronic pain and other health problems.</p>
<p>Massage therapy produces a significant reduction in the following symptoms: pain, fatigue, anxiety, muscle discomfort, nervousness, stress.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>It promotes improved blood and lymphatic circulation, which can lead to a reduction in overall inflammation the body<sup id="fnref1:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup><sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup><sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup>.</p>
<p>Massage therapy improves relaxation, circulation<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>, energy levels by promoting tranquility and emotional well-being in patients<sup id="fnref2:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>, thus contributing to a healthier and more active lifestyle.</p>
<p>The creation of the TrataMentœs company arose with the objective of preserving, restoring and promoting health as a whole.</p>
<p>The massage and wellness technician is specialized in the diagnosis, management, treatment and prevention of musculoskeletal and other related disorders, with techniques based on scientific evidence.</p>
<p>Today, science explains the effects of massage on the representation of pain in specific areas, leading to the relief of body tension by promoting relaxation throughout the body.</p>
<p>More recent studies show that sleep plays an increasingly important role and point to the benefits of manual therapy in reducing stress, improving sleep<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup>, increasing energy, and a more positive outlook on life.<sup id="fnref1:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup></p>
<p>Have you thought about giving your body the attention it deserves?</p>
<p>Contact TrataMentœs today to schedule your first appointment and start experiencing the many benefits of regular massage.</p>
<hr>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Alhamdoun A, Alomari K, al Qadire M. The Effects of Massage Therapy on Symptom Management among Patients WithCancer: A Systematic Review. Vol 3.; 2020.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref2:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Qin S, Xiao Y, Chi Z, et al. Effectiveness and safety of massage in the treatment of anxiety and depression in patients with cancer. Medicine. 2020;99(39):e22262. doi:10.1097/MD.0000000000022262&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Field T. Knee osteoarthritis pain in the elderly can be reduced by massage therapy, yoga and tai chi: A review. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2016;22:87-92. doi:10.1016/j.ctcp.2016.01.001&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>Moon HJ, Cho SH. A Comparison of the Immediate Effects of Alternate Methods to Medication in Lowering the Blood Pressure in Prehypertensive Patients. The Journal of Korean Physical Therapy. 2016;28(3):201-204. doi:10.18857/jkpt.2016.28.3.201&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>Hsu W, Guo S, Chang C. Back massage intervention for improving health and sleep quality among intensive care unit patients. Nurs Crit Care. 2019;24(5):313-319. doi:10.1111/nicc.12428&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/blog/os-beneficios-da-massagem-regular/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/blog/os-beneficios-da-massagem-regular/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><title>The benefits of regular massage</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<p>Please fill in the form below.</p>
<form name="contact" action="https://getform.io/" method="POST">
    <div class="input">
        <input type="text" placeholder="Name" name="name" class="p-4 bg-gray-200 border border-gray-200 focus:outline-none focus:bg-white focus:border-gray-500" required>
    </div>
    <div class="input">
        <input type="text" placeholder="Email" name="mail" class="p-4 bg-gray-200 border border-gray-200 focus:outline-none focus:bg-white focus:border-gray-500" required>
    </div>
    <div class="input">
        <input type="text" placeholder="Title" name="title" class="p-4 bg-gray-200 border border-gray-200 focus:outline-none focus:bg-white focus:border-gray-500" required>
    </div>
    <div class="input">
        <textarea rows="5" cols="30" placeholder="Message" name="message" class="p-4 bg-gray-200 border border-gray-200 focus:outline-none focus:bg-white focus:border-gray-500" required></textarea>
    </div>
    <input type="submit" value="Submit" class="px-8 py-2 duration-200 bg-gray-800 text-white cursor-pointer transition-colors hover:bg-gray-400">
</form>

<hr>
<p>Alternatively you can call or send a message to <a href="tel:+351934452743">+351 934 452 743</a></p>
]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/contact/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/contact/</link><title>Contact</title></item><item><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/search/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/search/</link><title>Search</title></item></channel></rss>