<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://tratamentes.pt/en/tags/stress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright>© Tratamentes</copyright><description>stress · Tratamentes</description><language>pt-pt</language><link>https://tratamentes.pt/en/tags/stress/</link><title>stress · Tratamentes</title><item><description><![CDATA[












































































    







    


<figure class=" d-flex    justify-content-center    paige-figure " >
    
        <div  class=" overflow-auto"   style="width: 40%" >
    

    

    <div class="text-center"><img   class="img-fluid rounded"  crossorigin="anonymous"   height="4000"  loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" src="/img/feche-as-maos-massageando-o-pescoco-do-paciente-min.f5e421841e8012c19e67095d9ef135bc568e0152f7147272cf9fb08205079baf.webp"    width="6000" ></div>

    
        <figcaption class="figure-caption  text-center" >Technician helps the client relax his back muscles, while applying one of the Swedish massage techniques</figcaption>
    

    

    
        </div>
    
</figure>



<p>A full body massage that uses smooth, fluid movements that help improve circulation and provide well-being.</p>
<p>The rush of everyday life generates several moments of stress and tension that accumulate and can negatively affect health and well-being. Relaxation massage is an excellent way to relieve and reduce these effects, through smooth and fluid movements that improve circulation, reduce tension, and promote a state of peace and tranquility.</p>
<p>Allow yourself to enjoy 60 minutes of tranquility, while recovering your energy and inner strength. Feel your body renewed and ready to face the day-to-day demands. Schedule your relaxation massage session now.</p>
<ul>
<li>Duration: 30 - 120 min.</li>
<li>Price: 49 € - 99 €</li>
</ul>
<p>For <strong><a href="/book-online">appointments</a></strong> and more information <strong><a href="/contact">contact me</a></strong></p>
<p><em><strong>Notes</strong></em>:</p>
<ul>
<li>You should indicate only one type of massage per session.</li>
<li>The transportation up to 5km from the center of Parede, Cascais county, is included in the price. For distances over 5km, an additional fee of 1.20 euros per kilometer.</li>
<li>Payments by MBWay, cash or immediate bank transfer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description><guid>https://tratamentes.pt/en/services/massagem-sueca/</guid><link>https://tratamentes.pt/en/services/massagem-sueca/</link><title>Swedish or Relaxation Massage</title></item></channel></rss>