<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="//tratamentes.pt/en/tags/wellness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright>© Tratamentes</copyright><description>wellness · Tratamentes</description><language>pt-pt</language><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/tags/wellness/</link><title>wellness · Tratamentes</title><item><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="improving-your-health-and-quality-of-life-today">Improving your health and quality of life today</h2>
<p>Do you know that in Portugal at least 1 in 3 people (37%) live with chronic pain?</p>
<p>Chronic pain is a health problem, worldwide, that affects millions of people and can have a major impact on their quality of life.</p>
<p>Living with chronic pain can be challenging as it affects your daily life and social roles.</p>
<p>In the biopsychosocial view, pain management, addresses the psychological and social consequences that chronic pain can have, as well as the importance of considering biological, psychological and social factors in the assessment and treatment of chronic pain. It is well known that chronic pain can affect quality of life, relationships and the ability to perform daily activities.</p>
<p>To better understand the causes of pain it is important to understand the difference between primary and secondary chronic pain for better pain management.</p>
<p>Primary chronic pain is pain that is not caused by any other health condition, but is a condition in itself. For example, chronic headache is a primary pain.</p>
<p>Secondary chronic pain is that which is caused by an underlying health condition, such as arthritis or nerve damage.</p>



















































































    


<figure class="     paige-figure " >
    

    

    <div class="text-center"><img   class="img-fluid rounded"  crossorigin="anonymous"   height="827"  loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" src="/img/classificacao-da-dor-de-acordo-com-a-iasp-2021.341622c90f2bab450f500f2408a7bc50c030785057aa51a22705c59101207a2a.png"    width="1128" ></div>

    
        <figcaption class="figure-caption  text-center" >Pain Classification according to IASP 2021</figcaption>
    

    

    
</figure>



<p>It is important to note that some chronic pain can be a sign of a more serious health problem and therefore you should be alert to some of the symptoms such as fever, unexplained weight loss, muscle weakness, changes in sensitivity or progressive and persistent pain. If you experience any of these symptoms you should seek medical attention immediately.</p>
<p>Along with other professionals, such as musculoskeletal therapists (massage therapists, osteopaths, physiotherapists), doctors and pharmacists, psychology also has a role in the treatment of chronic pain, observing case by case and intervening to help the brain communicate in a healthier way with the body, thus reorganising the patient&rsquo;s brain function.</p>
<p>To improve their health, it is essential to change habits and patterns of behaviour.</p>
<p>The individual with chronic pain is an integral part of the process, so it is important that there is communication, with information and guidance, to help them understand the importance of their active participation in the treatment. Their collaboration is fundamental for the success of the treatment, since they are the ones who must perform the tasks and make the changes in their daily lives that contribute to improving their state of health.</p>
<p>Massage has been by choice, a treatment option for chronic pain, in particular for secondary chronic pain.</p>
<p>Based on scientific evidence, massage is indicated by medicine, as a way to relieve pain in most cases. For example, a 2011 study published in the journal Annals of Internal Medicine<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>, another study shows, that after applying massage there is a significant reduction of pain<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup>.</p>
<p>For those who suffer on a daily basis with chronic pain, the use of musculoskeletal manual therapy, by a qualified professional is a condition for the relief of pain, in order to restore the functionality of the affected limb or the body in general.</p>
<p>It is always important to mention, that depending on the pain mechanism, there may be a need for a more comprehensive approach, including other health care professionals, with the purpose of supporting chronic pain management.</p>
<p>Contact TrataMentœs today to schedule your first appointment and start experiencing the many benefits of regular massage.</p>
<hr>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Cherkin, D. C., Sherman, K. J., Kahn, J., Wellman, R., Cook, A. J., Johnson, E., Erro, J., Delaney, K., &amp; Deyo, R. A. (2011). A comparison of the effects of 2 types of massage and usual care on chronic low back pain. Annals of Internal Medicine, 155(1), 1. <a href="https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-155-1-201107050-00002">https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-155-1-201107050-00002</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Adams, R., White, B., &amp; Beckett, C. (2010). The effects of massage therapy on pain management in the acute care setting. International journal of therapeutic massage &amp; bodywork, 3(1), 4–11. <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3091428/pdf/ijtmb-3-1-4.pdf">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3091428/pdf/ijtmb-3-1-4.pdf</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/blog/viver-com-dor-cr%C3%B3nica-em-portugal-compreender-as-causas-e-procurar-tratamento-eficaz/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/blog/viver-com-dor-cr%C3%B3nica-em-portugal-compreender-as-causas-e-procurar-tratamento-eficaz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><title>Living with Chronic Pain in Portugal</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="improving-your-health-and-quality-of-life-today">Improving your health and quality of life today</h2>
<p>As we age, our bodies tend to slow down physiological processes, and with the challenges of modern life, the body accumulates more and more stress, in the majority of the population, leading to chronic pain and other health problems.</p>
<p>Massage therapy produces a significant reduction in the following symptoms: pain, fatigue, anxiety, muscle discomfort, nervousness, stress.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>It promotes improved blood and lymphatic circulation, which can lead to a reduction in overall inflammation the body<sup id="fnref1:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup><sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup><sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup>.</p>
<p>Massage therapy improves relaxation, circulation<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>, energy levels by promoting tranquility and emotional well-being in patients<sup id="fnref2:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>, thus contributing to a healthier and more active lifestyle.</p>
<p>The creation of the TrataMentœs company arose with the objective of preserving, restoring and promoting health as a whole.</p>
<p>The massage and wellness technician is specialized in the diagnosis, management, treatment and prevention of musculoskeletal and other related disorders, with techniques based on scientific evidence.</p>
<p>Today, science explains the effects of massage on the representation of pain in specific areas, leading to the relief of body tension by promoting relaxation throughout the body.</p>
<p>More recent studies show that sleep plays an increasingly important role and point to the benefits of manual therapy in reducing stress, improving sleep<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup>, increasing energy, and a more positive outlook on life.<sup id="fnref1:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup></p>
<p>Have you thought about giving your body the attention it deserves?</p>
<p>Contact TrataMentœs today to schedule your first appointment and start experiencing the many benefits of regular massage.</p>
<hr>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Alhamdoun A, Alomari K, al Qadire M. The Effects of Massage Therapy on Symptom Management among Patients WithCancer: A Systematic Review. Vol 3.; 2020.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref2:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Qin S, Xiao Y, Chi Z, et al. Effectiveness and safety of massage in the treatment of anxiety and depression in patients with cancer. Medicine. 2020;99(39):e22262. doi:10.1097/MD.0000000000022262&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Field T. Knee osteoarthritis pain in the elderly can be reduced by massage therapy, yoga and tai chi: A review. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2016;22:87-92. doi:10.1016/j.ctcp.2016.01.001&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>Moon HJ, Cho SH. A Comparison of the Immediate Effects of Alternate Methods to Medication in Lowering the Blood Pressure in Prehypertensive Patients. The Journal of Korean Physical Therapy. 2016;28(3):201-204. doi:10.18857/jkpt.2016.28.3.201&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>Hsu W, Guo S, Chang C. Back massage intervention for improving health and sleep quality among intensive care unit patients. Nurs Crit Care. 2019;24(5):313-319. doi:10.1111/nicc.12428&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/blog/os-beneficios-da-massagem-regular/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/blog/os-beneficios-da-massagem-regular/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><title>The benefits of regular massage</title></item></channel></rss>