<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="//tratamentes.pt/en/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright>© Tratamentes</copyright><description>Services · Tratamentes</description><language>pt-pt</language><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/</link><title>Services · Tratamentes</title><item><description><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/massagem-desportiva.webp" alt="Technician helps the client relax his back muscles, while applying one of the Swedish massage techniques" title="Técnico auxilia cliente a relaxar a musculatura dorsal, ao aplicar uma das técnica da massagem sueca"></p>
<p>A full body massage that uses smooth, fluid movements that help improve circulation and provide well-being.</p>
<p>The rush of everyday life generates several moments of stress and tension that accumulate and can negatively affect health and well-being. Relaxation massage is an excellent way to relieve and reduce these effects, through smooth and fluid movements that improve circulation, reduce tension, and promote a state of peace and tranquility.</p>
<p>Allow yourself to enjoy 60 minutes of tranquility, while recovering your energy and inner strength. Feel your body renewed and ready to face the day-to-day demands. Schedule your relaxation massage session now.</p>
<ul>
<li>Duration: 60 min.</li>
<li>Price: 60 euros</li>
</ul>
<p>For <strong><a href="https://buk.pt/tratamentes">appointments</a></strong> and more information <strong><a href="/contact">contact me</a></strong></p>
<p><em><strong>Notes</strong></em>:</p>
<ul>
<li>You should indicate only one type of massage per session.</li>
<li>The transportation up to 5km from the center of Parede, Cascais county, is included in the price. For distances over 5km, an additional fee of 1.20 euros per kilometer.</li>
<li>Payments by MBWay, cash or immediate bank transfer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/massagem-sueca/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/massagem-sueca/</link><title>Swedish or Relaxation Massage</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/massagem-desportiva.webp" alt="Técnico auxilia atleta a recuperar" title="Técnico auxilia atleta a recuperar"></p>
<p>If you are an athlete or simply an amateur sportsman looking to improve your performance and prevent injuries, sports massage is a fundamental technique to achieve your goals.</p>
<p>With my experience and knowledge, I can offer a personalised massage that meets your specific needs.</p>
<p>From the application of appropriate techniques, such as manipulations and stretching, to the use of more up-to-date recovery protocols such as &ldquo;PEACE &amp; LOVE&rdquo;, I will be by your side at every stage, ensuring you have the best possible support.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t wait any longer to take care of your body in an efficient and professional way, schedule your sports massage session with me right now.</p>
<ul>
<li>Duration: 30 min.</li>
<li>Price: 30 euros</li>
</ul>
<p>For <strong><a href="https://buk.pt/tratamentes">appointments</a></strong> and more information <strong><a href="/contact">contact me</a></strong></p>
<p><em><strong>Notes</strong></em>:</p>
<ul>
<li>You should indicate only one type of massage per session.</li>
<li>The transportation up to 5km from the center of Parede, Cascais county, is included in the price. For distances over 5km, an additional fee of 1.20 euros per kilometer.</li>
<li>Payments by MBWay, cash or immediate bank transfer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/massagem-desportiva/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/massagem-desportiva/</link><title>Massagem Desportiva (pré e pós treino)</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[




































































    









    





    
        
    



    


<figure class=" d-flex   float-end   justify-content-center    ms-4  paige-figure "  style="width: 50%" >
    
        <div  class=" overflow-auto"  >
    

    
        <div class="d-table">
    

    <div class="text-center"><img   class="img-fluid rounded"  crossorigin="anonymous"   height="724"  loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="no-referrer" src="/img/DLM_1280x724.df1ab0720b5655f23630aa429feba9c64482094ba113ac1f9cdb4229f437b5fc.webp"    width="1280" ></div>

    
        <figcaption class="figure-caption  text-center"  style="caption-side: bottom; display: table-caption" >Application of DLM - Manual Lymphatic Drainage</figcaption>
    

    
        </div>
    

    
        </div>
    
</figure>



<p>If you have ever experienced swollen limbs or discomfort due to lymphedema, lymphatic drainage massage may help you.</p>
<p>This gentle massage technique is designed to stimulate the lymphatic system, which can help relieve the painful swelling caused by lymphedema.</p>
<p>In this blog article on &ldquo;<a href="/en/blog/drenagem-linfatica-manual/">Lymphatic drainage massage: What you need to know</a>&rdquo; is what you need to know about lymphatic drainage massage and how it can benefit your health.</p>
<p>Lymphatic drainage massage, also known as manual lymphatic drainage is a specialised massage technique that targets the lymphatic system.</p>
<p>The aim of lymph drainage massage is to improve the flow of lymph, which can become blocked due to surgery, injury or illness.</p>
<p>Lymphatic drainage massage is commonly used to relieve swelling and discomfort caused by lymphedema, one of the conditions that can occur, such as after breast cancer surgery.</p>
<ul>
<li>Price: 60 €</li>
<li>Duration: 60 min.</li>
</ul>
<p>You can <strong><a href="https://buk.pt/tratamentes">book a session here </a></strong> and for more information <strong><a href="/contact">contact me</a></strong></p>
<p>_ <strong>Notes</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>You must indicate only one type of massage per session.</li>
<li>The transportation until 5km from the centre of Parede, Cascais county, is included in the price. For distances greater than 5km, there is an additional charge of 1.20 euros per kilometer.</li>
<li>Payments by MBWay, cash or immediate bank transfer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/drenagem-linfatica-manual/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/drenagem-linfatica-manual/</link><title>Lymphatic Drainage Massage (LDM)</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<p>As a technician specialized in massage therapy I would like to suggest a natural and effective solution to treat a variety of physical and emotional problems.</p>
<p>Using proven techniques such as Muscle Energetic Technique, Muscle Inhibition Technique or Jones technique, Joint Mobilization, Neuromuscular Techniques and Harmonic Techniques, I can help treat chronic pain, muscle injuries, postural problems, anxiety, depression or insomnia.</p>
<p>I believe that massage therapy is much more than just a massage, and I am committed to providing the best possible treatment to help my clients achieve their health and wellness goals.</p>
<p>So if you are looking for a natural and effective way to treat your physical or emotional problems, I am here to help.</p>
<p>Duration: 60 min.
Price: 60 euros</p>
<p>For <strong><a href="https://buk.pt/tratamentes">appointments</a></strong> and more information <strong><a href="/contact">contact me</a></strong></p>
<p><em><strong>Notes</strong></em>:</p>
<ul>
<li>You should indicate only one type of massage per session.</li>
<li>The transportation up to 5km from the center of Parede, Cascais county, is included in the price. For distances over 5km, an additional fee of 1.20 euros per kilometer.</li>
<li>Payments by MBWay, cash or immediate bank transfer.</li>
</ul>
]]></description><guid>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/massagem-terapeutica/</guid><link>//tratamentes.pt/en/services/en/massagem-terapeutica/</link><title>Therapeutic Massage</title></item></channel></rss>