<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://tratamentes.pt/en/tags/musculoskeletal-disorders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><copyright>© Tratamentes</copyright><description>musculoskeletal-disorders · Tratamentes</description><language>pt-pt</language><link>https://tratamentes.pt/en/tags/musculoskeletal-disorders/</link><title>musculoskeletal-disorders · Tratamentes</title><item><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="improving-your-health-and-quality-of-life-today">Improving your health and quality of life today</h2>
<p>As we age, our bodies tend to slow down physiological processes, and with the challenges of modern life, the body accumulates more and more stress, in the majority of the population, leading to chronic pain and other health problems.</p>
<p>Massage therapy produces a significant reduction in the following symptoms: pain, fatigue, anxiety, muscle discomfort, nervousness, stress.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>It promotes improved blood and lymphatic circulation, which can lead to a reduction in overall inflammation the body<sup id="fnref1:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup><sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup><sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup>.</p>
<p>Massage therapy improves relaxation, circulation<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>, energy levels by promoting tranquility and emotional well-being in patients<sup id="fnref2:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>, thus contributing to a healthier and more active lifestyle.</p>
<p>The creation of the TrataMentœs company arose with the objective of preserving, restoring and promoting health as a whole.</p>
<p>The massage and wellness technician is specialized in the diagnosis, management, treatment and prevention of musculoskeletal and other related disorders, with techniques based on scientific evidence.</p>
<p>Today, science explains the effects of massage on the representation of pain in specific areas, leading to the relief of body tension by promoting relaxation throughout the body.</p>
<p>More recent studies show that sleep plays an increasingly important role and point to the benefits of manual therapy in reducing stress, improving sleep<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup>, increasing energy, and a more positive outlook on life.<sup id="fnref1:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup></p>
<p>Have you thought about giving your body the attention it deserves?</p>
<p>Contact TrataMentœs today to schedule your first appointment and start experiencing the many benefits of regular massage.</p>
<hr>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Alhamdoun A, Alomari K, al Qadire M. The Effects of Massage Therapy on Symptom Management among Patients WithCancer: A Systematic Review. Vol 3.; 2020.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref2:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Qin S, Xiao Y, Chi Z, et al. Effectiveness and safety of massage in the treatment of anxiety and depression in patients with cancer. Medicine. 2020;99(39):e22262. doi:10.1097/MD.0000000000022262&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Field T. Knee osteoarthritis pain in the elderly can be reduced by massage therapy, yoga and tai chi: A review. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2016;22:87-92. doi:10.1016/j.ctcp.2016.01.001&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>Moon HJ, Cho SH. A Comparison of the Immediate Effects of Alternate Methods to Medication in Lowering the Blood Pressure in Prehypertensive Patients. The Journal of Korean Physical Therapy. 2016;28(3):201-204. doi:10.18857/jkpt.2016.28.3.201&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>Hsu W, Guo S, Chang C. Back massage intervention for improving health and sleep quality among intensive care unit patients. Nurs Crit Care. 2019;24(5):313-319. doi:10.1111/nicc.12428&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>]]></description><guid>https://tratamentes.pt/en/blog/os-beneficios-da-massagem-regular/</guid><link>https://tratamentes.pt/en/blog/os-beneficios-da-massagem-regular/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><title>The benefits of regular massage</title></item></channel></rss>